Dareen: Uy Hedrix!
Dareen: Alam mo ba kung anong laro yan?
Hedrix: Badminton ata yan pre
Dareen: Tara! Laruin naten, mukhang masaya't maganda.
Hedrix: Sige tara laruin naten!
Hedrix: Kaso hindi ko alam kung paano yan laruen eh
Hedrix: Ikaw alam mo ba?
Dareen: Hinde ren ehh, paano ba?
TV: Today, teens try to play badminton
TV: Will they be able to play it properly?
TV: Find out on Teens Play,
TV: Broadcast at 5 o'clock pm
TV: Only here on the program.
Dareen: Hi! Pwede ba kami sumali sa inyo?
Ria: Tara G!
Both: Can you help us know more about badminton?
Announcer: And here's your host,
Host: Welcome to the first episode of What is That Thing?
Host: Where we look deeper into popular things on the internet
Host: Today, as our first episode here on What is That Thing,
Host: We will look deeper into the History, Rules & Procedures, and Health-Related Information about badminton.
Host: So, to start us off, let's go to our Resident Journalist, Lariesh Buenviaje, to give us background information about badminton.
Lariesh: Did you know that badminton was developed in British India?
Lariesh: From the earlier game of Battledore & Shuttlecock European play?
Lariesh: And became to be dominated by Denmark, but the game became popular in Asia,
Lariesh: With recent competition dominated by China.
Lariesh: Early on, the game was also known as 'Poona' or 'Poonah'
Lariesh: After the garrison town of 'Poona' (Pune).
Lariesh: Where it was particularly popular,
Lariesh: And where the first rules of the game were drawn up in '1873'.
Lariesh: Badminton first debuted as a summer Olympic sport in 1992 with four events.
Lariesh: Men's Singles, Women's Singles, Men's Doubles, and Women's Doubles
Lariesh: Mixed Doubles was added four years later.
Lariesh: At high levels of play, the sport demands excellent fitness:
Lariesh: Players require aerobic stamina, agility, strength, speed, and precision.
Lariesh: It is also a technical sport, requiring good motor coordination and the development of sophisticated racquet movements.
Host: So now that we know badminton's history and background.
Host: Let us now go to our sports analyst, Jezzel Anne, to give us the Rules & Procedures of badminton.
Jezzel: So now, let's proceed to the Procedures & Rules of the game.
Jezzel: First, are the rules.
Jezzel: The rules are.
Host: Let us now know, what are the common injuries on playing this sport.
Host: So let us now go to our health reporter, Clarisse Kyt, to know more information.
Clarisse: Common Sport Injuries
Clarisse: Here are the common badminton injuries that you might get when you play.
Host: So that is all we have for today, here at What is That Thing?
Host: Stay tuned to The Paragon, Channel 42 for our next segment, Teens Play.
Host: We hope to see you again next week!
Robert: This is Robert, for What is That Thing.